Curriculum Vitae

DR. MUHAMAD AZRIN BIN OMAR @ NAWI

Current Designation:

Deputy Director (Medical II), National Cancer Institute (*Institut Kanser Negara*, IKN) Ministry of Health Malaysia (KKM)

Personal Data



 MyKad:
 790312105725

 Date of Birth:
 12th March 1979

 Contact No.:
 +60192787574

Email address: drazrin@nci.gov.my

drazrin@gmail.com

Marital Status: Married

Professional Profile

A qualified medical doctor with experience in clinical and administrative work.

Experience of working closely together with clinical consultants, specialists, and managers in Hospital setting; and administrators in charge of policy making in Ministry of Health.

Loves working in a team and has years of experience doing voluntary work with several

Non-Governmental Organisations.

Academic Qualifications

2003 M.D. (UKM)

Faculty of Medicine, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia

(Anticipated to graduate in March

2023)

Azman Hashim International Business School, Universiti

Teknologi Malaysia:

Candidate for Master's in Business Administration (Healthcare

Concentration)



Working Experience

May 2003 – January 2005	Housemanship Training
Januari, 2000	Department of Obstetrics and Gynaecology, Hospital Selayang
	Department of Internal Medicine, Hospital Selayang
	Department of Orthopaedic and Traumatology, Hospital Selayang
	Department of General Surgery, Hospital Selayang
	Department of Paediatrics, Hospital Selayang
January 2005 –	Medical Officer
December 2006	Department of Urology, Hospital Selayang
January 2007 –	Medical Officer
April 2018	Department of General Surgery, Hospital Selayang
May 2015 –	Wound Team Coordinator
April 2018	Hospital Selayang
	Key responsibilities:
	 Accept referrals for acute and chronic wound management
	 Conduct wound management training and courses for medical officers and healthcare personnel
August - September	Medical Officer
2015	Tabung Haji Medical Team
July-August	Key responsibilities:
2016	- Provide medical service to Malaysian Pilgrims in
	Makkah and Madinah during Hajj Season - Involvement in preparatory courses for pilgrims in
	Malaysia

April – May 2018

Senior Principal Assistant Director

Medical Care Quality Section, Medical Development Division,

Ministry of Health, Malaysia

Key responsibilities:

- Providing personal assistance and operational support to Head of Unit
- Involved in preparation of policies and national program including:
 - Revision of National Policy on Infection Control Procedure
 - Wound Care Quick reference
 - Antimicrobial resistance program
- Secretariat member of National Infection Control Committee, National Wound Care Committee

June 2018 – February 2020

Special Officer to Minister of Health

Ministry of Health, Malaysia

Key responsibilities:

- Provision of technical input and information to the Minister in preparation for Cabinet and Post-Cabinet Meetings, and Parliamentary sessions.
- Work together with the administrative office of the Minister in arrangement of day-to-day office events and scheduling.
- Represents the Minister's office in meetings involving other departments in the Ministry.
- Plays an active part in Minister's office team for short-, mid- and long-term planning.

January 2019 – February 2020

Head of Secretariat

Health Advisory Council (HAC)

Key responsibilities:

- Management of dates, meeting venue and logistics in accordance with the schedule of the Chairperson and Members of the HAC
- Preparation of reports related to the meeting agenda, and preparation and distribution of meeting minutes

July – August 2020

Acting Deputy Director (Medical II)

Institut Kanser Negara

Key responsibilities:

Hospital administration and management especially in issues related to medical support services.

April 2020 - August 2021

Head of Unit

Unit Pengurusan Perubatan, Institut Kanser Negara

Key responsibilities:

- Coordinator for certification of ISO 22301:2019
 Business Continuity Management System (BCMS) for IKN
 - o Lead Auditor for the Internal Audit Team
 - Preparation and revision of related policy and guidelines documents
- Assist the hospital administration in other matters including:
 - Full Paying Patient Scheme
 - o Coordination for *Hospital Kluster* Initiatives
 - Monitoring of Casemix system implementation
 - o Coordination of Medicolegal related matters
 - Non-Clinical Incident management

August 2021 – Present

Deputy Director (Medical II)

Institut Kanser Negara

Key responsibilities:

- Hospital administration and management especially in relation to clinical support services.
- Oversee the Clinical Support Directorate which include:
 - Information Technology Department
 - Pharmacy Department
 - Dietetics and Catering
 - o Traditional and Complementary Medicine Unit
 - Physiotherapy Unit
 - o Medical Social Work Unit
 - National Cancer Registry
 - Clinical Research Center
 - Medical Record Department
 - Quality Unit
 - o Public Health Unit
 - Health Education Unit
 - Infection Control Unit
 - Nursing Unit
 - Supervisor Unit
 - o Central Sterilisation and Supply Unit
 - Wound Care Unit
- Involvement in committees for certification of IKN in:
 - ISO 22301:2019 Business Continuity Management System (BCMS)
 - ISO Information Security Management System (ISMS) ISO 27001:2013
 - Malaysian Society for Quality in Health (MSQH accreditation

<u>Awards</u>

Anugerah Perkhidmatan Cemerlang (APC) 2008, Jabatan Kesihatan Negeri Selangor

Volunteer Experience

Kelab Sukan dan Kebajikan IKN	Chairman
(KESKIK)	2021 – Present
Yayasan Prihatin Insan	Chairman, Board of Trustees
(YPI)	2020 – Present
Pertubuhan Kebajikan Serantau Muslim	Deputy Chairman
(Serantau Muslim)	2017 – Present
Persatuan Alumni SAS 96	Secretary 2017 – Present
Pertubuhan Pengukuhan dan Pengupayaan	Chairman
Kesihatan Masyarakat	2017 – Present
Pertubuhan Amal Perubatan Ibnu Sina	Vice President
Malaysia (PAPISMA)	2014 – 2016